OZGUR LEBLEBICI

Mechanical Engineer International Welding Engineer (IWE) Quality Control Engineer

Address : Fair Lawn, New Jersey, USA E – mail : oleblebici@yahoo.com Mobile : +1 (201) 316 71 71

PROFILE

Engineer looking for job opportunities with my 18-year-experience in construction departments in industrial plant and pipeline projects. In my experience, I obtained the abilities – organization and time management, teamwork, good communication, problem solving, good flexibility, negotiation, quick adaptation, open and willing to learn.

KEY SKILLS

• Steel Structural Manufacturing

• Welding

• Non Destructive Testing (NDT)

• Project Management

• Storage Tank Erection

• Pressure Vessel Manufacturing (acc. ASME Standarts)

• Equipment Erection

• Pipe Manufacturing

• Piping

• Pipeline erection

• Steel Erection

• Standarts (ASME, API, EN)

• Exotic Welding

• Hydrostatic Testing

• Commissioning

Method Statement and Procedure

• Quality Assurance & Quality Control

• Documentation

• Reporting

• Planning

• Microsoft Office Programs

EDUCATION

Gesellschaft für Schweißtechnik International mbH, München / GERMANY

International Welding Engineer, Graduation Year 2009

Dokuz Eylul University, Izmir / TURKEY

Mechanical Engineering DepartmentGraduation Year 2004

WORK EXPERIENCES

IDEAL CELIK AS, Izmir / Turkey

06/2005 - 12/2006

Habas Demir Celik Fabrikaları, Izmir / Turkey

Position: Steel Structural Engineer

- Ideal Celik is one of the subcontractors of Habas
- Managed all erectors and welders
- Responsibility for following up production and assembly of steel construction
- Material supply
- Cost calculation
- Reporting

Position: Equipment & Pipe Erection Engineer

• I worked in two projects

Proiects in Gama Endustri Tesisleri AS

- Vyksa Casting & Rolling Complex Project, Vyksa / Russia
- Responsible erection of equipments in Casting and Scrap Yard areas
- Manage teams
- Material supply
- Kept in touch with supervisors of contractor firms
- Weekly-erection plans and monthly-erection reports.
- Prepared documentation

• Qatargas QCS 3&4 Onshore Project, Ras Laffan / Qatar

- Erection of equipments and pipes in Inlet Area
- Manage teams and material supply
- Prepare RFI and handover documents
- Manage subcontractor
- Control of pipe erection and subcontractor
- Programing erection
- Organized teams
- Keep relations with supervisors of contractor and subcontractor.

GIMAS MAKINA SANAYI AS, Izmir / TURKEY

09/2010 - 11/2011

Position: Mechanical & Welding Engineer

- The company authorised me for welding activities
- Followed manufacturing in factory and subcontractors' workshops
- Coordination of client, manufacturing team and quality team.
- Performed all requirements of projects
- Prepared new quality documentation system of projects according to EN and ASME standarts
- Renewed all WPSs according to EN and ASME standarts
- Performed welder qualification tests
- Leaded manufacturing for boilers and pressure vessels
- Prepared all documents for manufacturing authorization for boilers and pressure vessels by ASME
- Organized and followed non-destructive tests on manufacturing
- Controlled all pre-assembling and run tests
- Reported weekly-manufacturing

Projects in GIMAS

- 3 x 500 MW Aberthaw Unit 7 & 9 Thermal Power Plant Project / RWE npower 12 pieces of separators and mill stands
- 685 MW x 2 Chhattisgarh Thermal Power Plant Project / GMR Energy Doosan 14 pieces of coal separators & mill stands
- 2590 MW Orot Rabin Coal Power Station Project / Israel Electric Coorperation 12 pieces of separators and mill stands
- Gulf Flour Abu Dhabi Project / Mikropul

Flourspar dust filters

■ Kirikkale Refinery / TUPRAS

Pressure Vessels, 5 drums and 3 exchangers

■ Nowokusnezk & Nizhniy Tagil Coal Power Plants / Paul Wurth S.A.

3 pieces of coal separators & mill stands

ENKA INSAAT SAN. AS, Istanbul / TURKEY

11/2011 - 08/2012

Shell Early Production Facilities Project, Majnoon, Basra / Iraq

Position: Mechanical & Welding Engineer

- Supervised contruction team for steel structure and piping area of this project
- Prepared weekly programs
- Coordinated activities with erection team
- Transportation of pipes
- Material supply
- Documentation
- Reporting

ELDORADO GOLD CORP.

08/2012 - 02/2013

TÜPRAG METAL MADENCILIK TIC. SAN. VE LTD. STI, Usak / TURKEY

Position: Welding Engineer / Specialist

- Worked in construction team
- Supervised new pipelines on mine
- Monitored subcontractor's work
- Hydrotesting
- Followed quality issues for new lines
- Performed welder qualification tests
- Surveillance quality activities of manufacturing steel structures and equipment installation
- Monitoring of subcontractor activities
- Reporting

TEKFEN CONSTRUCTION AND INSTALLATION CO. INC.

03/2013 - 11/2013

Dow & Saudi Aramco Sadara Project, Propylene Oxide Plant, Jubail / SAUDI ARABIA

Position: Welding Engineer / Specialist

- Prepared all quality documentation, method statements, procedures
- Managed welders on workshop and site
- Performed welder qualification tests
- Prepared and performed WPSs & PQRs according to ASME standarts
- Supervised and kept in touch with client's supervisors and inspectors
- Reporting

YAMATA INDUSTRIAL PROJECTS CONSTRUCTION LTD.

06/2014 - 04/2015

Lukoil VGO Project, Volgograd / RUSSIA

Position: Quality Control Engineer

- Started firstly in piping workshop
- Managed QC team in workshop
- Organized NDT activities
- After completion of manufacturing in workshop, I started to work on site.
- Supervised and kept in touch with client's supervisors and inspectors
- Managed welder qualification tests
- Monitored welder tests and hydrotesting
- Followed exotic welding
- Completed missing procedures and documentation
- Reporting

MOD MODULER MUHENDISLIK LTD STI, Manisa / TURKEY

04/2015 -11/2015

Position: Owner / Company Partner

- I set up a construction company with two partners
- Followed all legal procedures and documentation
- Prepared most bids for new projects
- Calculated cost estimation

RINA DENIZCILIK VE BELGELENDIRME SIRKETI

11/2015 -05/2016

GAP Insaat AS, Turkmenbashi International Seaport Project, Baku / AZERBAIJAN

Position: QC Lead Engineer

- This company followed QC activities in a pipe manufacturing factory.
- Organized Third Party QC team
- Monitored inspections, documentation, NDT activities, reports.
- Monitored welder qualification tests
- Reporting

SONMEZ METAL END. VE TİC AS

05/2016 - 05/2017

Mary-3 Combined Cycle Power Plant Project, Mary / TURKMENISTAN

Position: QA/QC Lead Engineer

- Organized QC & Welding team
- This subcontractor company was authorized for all QC activities with main contractor.
- Managed recruitment of inspectors and welders, tested inspectors and welders
- Prepared all documentation, quality procedures, method statements, WPSs & PQRs
- Reporting
- Monitored inspections, NDT activities, reports.
- Supervised and kept in touch with client's supervisors and inspectors

SHAMS AL SABAH CO.

01/2018 - 07/2018

ENI - Zubair Permanent Power Plant (740MW) Generation Project, Basra / IRAQ

Position : Crude Oil Tank Engineer

- I was responsible as a tank engineer in tank area.
- Managed erection team.
- Prepared and monitored erection and documentation of tanks.
- Followed quality activities, followed reports.
- Managed hydrotesting.

FREELANCE ENGINEER / INSPECTOR

08/2018 - 04/2022

- Project Management
- Manufacturing and erection of pipe and steel structures
- Mechanical Equipment Erection
- Storage Tank Erection
- Pressure Vessel Manufacturing and Inspections
- Inspection and Documentation of Storage Tanks
- Inspections of Steel Structural Manufacturing and Erection
- Inspections of Pipe Manufacturing and Erection
- RIR Inspections
- Hydrostatic Tests
- Documentation, Preparation of Quality Activities
- Welder Tests

Main Projects as Freelancer

• Karbala Refinery Project, South Karbala / Iraq

Position: Crude Oil Tank Construction Engineer

- I was responsible for 8 oil tanks as only an engineer in Iraqi local company.
- Kept in touch with site manager, construction manager and QC team.
- Organized and managed erection teams.
- Supervised and kept in touch with client's supervisors and inspectors
- Followed-up QC activities
- Monitored Erection, QC and NDT documentation.

• Tekfen Ceyhan Fabrication Facilities, Ceyhan Adana / Turkey

Position: Project Engineer

- I was responsible as a project engineer for Parnaiba Piperack Project on behalf of Techint Company.
- Kept in touch with fabrication manager, quality manager, production manager and engineers.
- Solving the issues with Tekfen Fabrication management.
- Reported all activities and documentation to Techint Company.
- Controlled products and manufacturing according to project contract and requirements.
- Followed-up manufacturing and quality activities.
- Monitored manufacturing progress, quality and documentation.

• Aritas Cryogenics Fabrication Facilities, Bandirma, Balıkesir / Turkey

Position: Pressure Vessel Inspector

- I was responsible as a presurre vessel inspector for Arctic LNG 2 Project on behalf of Novatek Company.
- Kept in touch with QA/QC manager, engineers.
- Followed-up all QC activities of all pressure vessels.
- Controlled all steps according to project contract & requirements and ASME standarts.
- Monitored QC and NDT documentation
- Reported all activities and documentation to Novatek Company.

• Katmerciler Izmir Factory, Cigli, Izmir / Turkey

Position: QC Inspector

- I was responsible as a QC inspector for aluminum transportation tanks on behalf of DNV GL (WOQOD) Company.
- Kept in touch with QA/QC manager, engineers, TSE engineers.
- Followed-up all QC activities of aluminum tanks.
- Controlled all steps according to project contract & requirements.
- Witnessed hydrotesting..
- Monitored QC and NDT documentation
- Reported all activities and documentation.

NALBANT GROUP CELIK KONSTRUKSIYON AS, Izmir / TURKEY 04/2022 – 11/2022

Position: Welding Engineer

- Managed welders on workshop and site
- Performed welder qualification tests
- Prepared and performed WPSs & PORs according to ASME standarts
- Supervised and kept in touch with client's supervisors and inspectors
- Prepared all documentation, quality procedures, method statements, WPSs & PQRs
- Reporting
- Monitored inspections, NDT activities, reports.

CERTIFICATES (As per SNT-TC-1A Documents)

- International Welding Engineering (IWE) Diploma
- ASNT Penetrant Testing Level II
- ASNT Magnetic Particle Testing Level II
- ASNT Radiographic Testing Level II
- ASNT Ultrasonic Testing Level II
- ASNT Visual Testing Level II

LANGUAGES

Turkish (Native)
 English (Advanced)
 Russian (Intermediate)
 German (Pre-Intermediate)

COURSES

Operations & Maintenance of Belt Conveyors

Quality Management System and ISO 9001

Development of Management Skills

CMA / Usak – Turkey 2012

Tested / İstanbul – Turkey 2010

RINA / Doha – Qatar 2008

Elginkan / Manisa – Turkey 2002 Elginkan / Manisa – Turkey 2002

Elginkan / Manisa – Turkey 2001

Welding Technics

PLC & Electropneumatics
Hydraulics & Pneumatics

REFERENCES

Mevlut OzcanDeputy Project ManagerMobile: +90 541 656 44 46Ilhan OmerogluQA/QC ManagerMobile: +90 539 384 85 67Alper KartalConstruction ManagerMobile: +90 532 466 35 35

PERSONEL

Marial Status : Single

Place of Birth : Usak, TURKEY

Date of Birth : 1979